本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：猴子 马蒂 米苏 LyraL 费列罗西瓜 句号
时间轴：小怡子 潘叔
■
校对：饿得慌  坏D小泡
后期：飞飞   总监：丢丢
■
诉 讼 双 雄
第一季 第八集
安厦建筑公司
露西尔
Lucille.
这看起来不错嘛
Hey, it's looking good.
-你应该有好消息吧  -没错
- Tell me you got good news. - I do.
安厦建筑公司的过渡贷款通过审批了
Stable Shelters' bridge loan has just been approved.
哈维在银行托了些关系
Harvey pulled some strings at the bank.
哈维  很高兴见到你
Good to see you, Harvey.
我发现你有点排斥体力劳动啊
I figured you was allergic to manual labor.
露西尔  必要时我还是会干点脏活的
I'll get my hands dirty if I have to, Lucille.
但我相信齐家才能治国
But I believe charity begins at home.
是啊  从你戴的劳力士手表
Yeah, and based on that Rolex you wear,
我就看出你所爱的事业正蒸蒸日上
I'd say that your favorite cause is doing pretty good.
你需要在这签个字
We're gonna need your signature here.
15%的利息
15% interest?
他们担心安厦建筑公司的偿付能力
They're worried about Stable Shelters' solvency.
他们还担心
They're worried?
他们应该去做执行董事
They should try being executive director.
如果你追不回
If you don't recover the money
安东尼・马兹洛从我们这里挪用的资金
that Anthony Mazlo embezzled from us,
这些计划就都泡汤了
every one of these projects goes dark.
除非你的公寓
Unless you got a spare room or two
有地方收留几千户家庭
for a couple thousand families in your condo.
我不太喜欢跟别人合住
I'm not really a roommate kind of guy.
今天下午哈维就会听取马兹洛的副手
Harvey's deposing Elliot Perkins, Mazlo's number two,
埃利奥特・珀金斯的证词
this afternoon.
珀金斯一定清楚这点
Perkins had to have knowledge of this,
他会供出他的老板的
and he's going to give up his boss.
我向你保证  稍等
That's a promise. Excuse me.
看看  去希腊旅游时
Check it out. Mazlo spent $500
马兹洛有一晚在宠物日托所花了五百美元
a night on doggie daycare on his trip to Greece.
希腊
Greece.
怎么了
What?
-没事  -说
- Oh, nothing. - Tell me.
我的第一次就是在希腊
My first time was in greece.
天呐  你在想象当时的情景  是吧
My god, you're picturing that right now, aren't you?
没办法  我是视觉动物
I have no choice. I'm a visual person.
你们俩真可爱
You two are really adorable.
还有两天就要庭审了
We're 48 hours from trial,
你们还像参加野营的孩子一样闲聊
and you're gossiping like two 12-year-olds at sleepaway camp.
听好了
Listen up.
露西尔・杰克森不只是安厦建筑公司的头儿
Lucille Jackson's not just the head of Stable Shelters, okay?
她还是我们律所
She also sits on the board of directors
好几个大客户的董事会成员
of several of our largest clients.
因此如果我们输了
So if we lose this case,
我觉得她不会对我们手软的
I doubt that her generosity's going to extend to us.
-我会...  -来我办公室
- I would-- - In my office.
带上清泉钻井公司的上市资料
Bring the Clarity Drilling IPO.
杰罗姆・詹森来了  快点
Jerome Jensen's here. Come on.
我们得全力攻克露西尔的案子  哈维
Lucille's case is all hands on deck, Harvey.
你不可以就这么...
You can't just--
我可以  你奈我何
I can, and I am.
我们难道不是在合作吗
I thought we're working on this together.
路易  我们是在合作
Yeah, we are, Louis.
就像高尔夫球手和球僮一样
Same way a golfer and his caddy work together.
尽管如此
Be that as it may,
我们要在15分钟后向埃利奥特・珀金斯取证  所以...
We are deposing Elliot Perkins in 15 minutes, so--
珀金斯的事可以等等
Perkins can wait.
你只要事先把9号杆给我好好擦亮就行了
Just make sure that my 9 iron is nice and shiny when I get there.
好吗  来吧  迈克
Okay? Come on, Mike.
哈维
Harvey.
杰罗姆・詹森  这位是迈克・罗斯
Jerome Jensen, meet Mike Ross.
他有首次公开募股的最新信息
He's got the latest on the IPO.
-你好  迈克  -詹森先生
- Hello, Mike. - Mr. Jensen.
我不是来谈生意的  哈维
I'm not here to talk about my business, Harvey.
我女儿貌似惹上麻烦了
Looks like my daughter might be getting into some trouble.
米德里德・维纽斯基
Mildred Wisnewski.
罗拉用假身份证干什么
What's Lola doing with a fake I.D.?
这就是我想让你们调查的
Well, that's what I hope you can find out.
这是她在朋友的成人礼上点饮料的时候
It slipped out of her purse when she was ordering a drink
从包里掉出来的
at a friend's bar mitzvah.
有什么头绪吗
Any idea what it's about?
我和罗拉这几年闹得挺僵的
My relationship with Lola's been rocky for a few years.
我问她什么  她都不说实话
If I asked her, she'd just lie.
其实  知不知道无所谓
Truth is, I don't need to know.
我只想请你帮我解决这事
I just need you to take care of it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
哈维在搞什么鬼
What the hell is Harvey doing?
他应该去对埃利奥特・珀金斯取证
He's supposed to be deposing Elliot Perkins.
他跟客户在一起
He's with a client.
我不管  我们要取证
I don't care. We have a deposition.
别乱来  路易
Don't even try it, Louis.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
咱们从头聊  好吗
Let's--let's just start over. Okay?
-你好  唐娜  -你好
- Hi, Donna. - Hi.
你知道我喜欢你的  对吧
You know I like you, right?
但是在公司的食物链中
But in the firm's food chain,
我是座头鲸  而你只是浮游生物
I am a humpback whale, and you are phytoplankton.
1997年6月3日
June 3, 1997.
这对我不是什么特殊的日子
that date means nothing to me.
真的吗
Doesn't it?
谁告诉你的
Who told you?
重要的不是我怎么知道的
Is the important thing how I know
而是我知道了
or that I know?
哈维知道吗
Does Harvey know?
有可能
He can.
我可以给你钱
I'm going to pay you.
只是我现在没带现金
I just don't have cash on me right now.
不过我会让诺玛到取款机去取
So I'm gonna just tell Norma to run her old ass out to the ATM
然后立刻送来  好吗
and then bring it back in a jiff, all right?
我不要你的钱  路易
I don't want your money, Louis.
我只想让你...
I just want you to--
无视我吧  就当我没来过
I was not here. I was not here.
我没来过
I was not here.
好了  我们开始吧
All right, let's get started, shall we?
不是由哈维・斯佩克特来主持取证吗
Isn't Harvey Specter leading this deposition?
他派我来了
He sent me.
珀金斯先生
Now, Mr. Perkins,
我的第一个问题是
my first question to you is...
你晚上睡得好吗
do you sleep well at night?
当然好了
of course you do,
因为你有房子住  有自来水用
'cause you have a roof and a bed and running water,
相比之下
and by contrast,
上千户的家庭即将露宿街头
thousands of families are gonna be sleeping on the street
就因为你偷了公司的钱
when Stable Shelters is forced to suspend their operations,
致使安厦建筑公司的运作搁浅
all because of the money that you stole.
我从没偷过任何东西
I never stole anything.
你是马兹洛的副手
You're Mazlo's number two.
你不承认有人挪用公款吗
Money was embezzled. Do you deny that?
-当然不承认  -拜托  罗伯特
- Absolutely. - Please, Robert,
我知道你这个总顾问只做些琐碎的事
I know as general counsel you just basically push paper,
但请你警告珀金斯先生
But will you please warn Mr. Perkins
作伪证的后果
about the penalties of perjury.
我没听到什么伪证
Look, I'm not aware of any perjury.
我们知道你在开曼群岛有个账户
We know about your account in the Caymans.
-两千万美元  -别搞笑了
- $20 million. - Are you kidding me?
那笔交易是合法的
That transaction was legitimate.
等我把这个公诸于众  你就得颜面扫地
Oh, when I take this public, you're gonna be disgraced.
你的妻子  孩子  全家都要颜面扫地
Your wife, your children, your whole family, disgraced.
请你尊重我的委托人
Would you show my client some respect--
而且那笔交易和公司没有任何关系
and that transaction had nothing to do with the firm.
扯淡
Bullshit.
那笔钱不是马兹洛给你的赃款  就是封口费
You either took your cut from Mazlo, or it was hush money.
不管怎样  除非供出马兹洛
Either way, you're gonna live the rest of your life
不然你下半辈子都只能做个下等人了
as a pariah, or you give up Mazlo now.
这是在取证还是审讯
Is this a deposition or an inquisition?
真是荒谬  我可以把记录给你看
This is ridiculous. I can show you the records.
你当然可以  因为就是你
Oh, sure you can. Because you're the guy
捏造了按揭证券的亏损
who invented losses in mortgage-backed securities
其实你根本就没买
when you never even bought them.
这没我的份
I had no part in that.
但是你很清楚这件事  却没有阻拦
But you were aware of it, and you did nothing about it.
够了  路易
Come on, Louis.
我可以喝杯水吗
Can I get a glass of water, please?
不可以  我们这里没水
You can't get any water. We don't have any.
只要你供出马兹洛  就不用受这份罪了
You give up Mazlo now, and this all stops.
好了  这样吧
All right, that's-- that's it.
我的委托人需要休息一下
My client needs a break.
我们十分钟后再继续
We can continue this in ten minutes.
我才刚刚开始
I'm just getting started.
我不明白了  她看起来很可爱
I don't get it. She looks so sweet.
别被照片蒙了
Don't let the photo fool you.
她可不是邻家女孩
She's less "girl next door"
更像是个不良少女
and more "girl with the dragon tattoo."
安厦建筑公司的案子让我无暇他顾
Look, my plate's full with Stable Shelters.
我要你去调查杰罗姆的女儿
I need you to look into Jerome's daughter.
你怎么不请个私家侦探
Why didn't you just hire a private investigator?
因为一旦出现问题
Because if there's a problem,
侦探解决不了
an investigator can't fix it.
我不只是杰罗姆的律师
I'm not just a lawyer to Jerome, okay?
我就像电影《教父》里的罗伯特・杜瓦尔
I'm--I'm more like Robert Duvall in the Godfather.
罗伯特・杜瓦尔:教父的养子  职业为律师
是他的顾问
His consigliere.
好吧
Okay.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Uh, nothing.
就是如果你是他的罗伯特・杜瓦尔
Just if you're his Robert Duvall,
你转而拜托我
you're coming to me,
所以严格来讲  我就是你的罗伯特・杜瓦尔
so technically i'm your Robert Duvall.
你是我的弗雷多
You're my Fredo.
弗雷多:教父的次子  最终被弟弟麦克所杀
弗雷多  不是
Fredo? No.
罗伯特  珀金斯怎么了
Robert, what the hell happened to Perkins?
问问你那凶狠的同事吧
Ask that pit bull of yours.
不  实际上
No, actually.
我更喜欢女按摩师
I prefer a female masseuse?
如果...  我一会打给你好吗
If that-- can I call you right back?
一会就好  好的  再见
Right back. Okay, bye.
珀金斯刚才被抬上担架
Perkins just got wheeled out on stretcher.
他是中暑了吧
Well, he couldn't handle the heat.
说不定是假装的
He's probably faking it.
你脑子在想什么  我还没来就开始取证
What were you thinking, starting that deposition without me?
我怎么知道  也许你正忙着...
I don't know. Maybe if you were doing your jo--
-不  -怎么了
- Oh, no. - What?
盖勒发来消息  珀金斯没有装病
It's from Geller. Perkins wasn't faking anything.
我们断送了安东尼・马兹洛的性命
Our best chance to nail Anthony Mazlo's dead.
他不愿配合取证
Well, he blew off the deposition,
我只是想让他知道我们不是好惹的
so I was just picking up the slack.
我是想让珀金斯不安
I was letting Perkins sweat.
这是我的策略  但全让你搞砸了
It was a tactic, which you completely undermined.
他被我整得远远不是焦躁这么简单了
I believe I made him sweat and then some.
你对自己的所作所为很骄傲吗
Are you actually proud of what you did?
就我个人而言
As far as I'm concerned,
无论那家伙发生了什么事
whatever happened to that guy
都是他咎由自取
was a result of his own guilt,
我也不会因为向他这个罪犯取证
and I will not apologize for deposing a criminal
而诚恳道歉的
in a vigorous manner.
珀金斯的死  让案件变得棘手
Losing Perkins is a complication.
我们得加倍努力
We're just gonna have to work harder
追查出马兹洛的资金下落
to unearth Mazlo's money trail.
就目前的情况
As for what happened,
我已经和医院交涉过了
I've spoken to the hospital,
死因是肺栓塞
and cause of death was a pulmonary embolism.
跟你没有任何关系
It was nothing you did.
那这功劳能算我的吗
Would it be okay if I took the credit?
路易  我要和哈维单独说两句
Louis, I need to have a word with Harvey.
好吧
Okay.
金融犯罪案是那家伙的专长
Financial crime is that man's forte.
我承认  他越权了
Yes, he overstepped his rank,
但我不打算玉石俱焚
but I'm not about to throw the baby out with the bathwater.
路易就是那块"石头"
Louis is the bathwater.
信不信由你  哈维
Believe it or not, harvey,
跟你合作可不是件容易事
You can be a real pain in the ass to work with too.
我觉得我很好相处啊
I get along with me just fine.
我不打算告诉露西尔・杰克森
Yes, well, I'm not about to tell Lucille Jackson
我们打不赢这场官司是由于我们合不来
that we didn't win because we couldn't work together.
你得适应和路易一起工作
You need to figure out how to collaborate with Louis.
罗拉・詹森假身份证上的名字
So the name on Lola Lensen's fake I.D.
并不是她凭空捏造的
wasn't just pulled from thin air.
而是清泉钻井公司的一名财务总监助理
Belongs to an assistant controller at Clarity Drilling.
跟我说这些干嘛
You're telling me this why?
不是你让我查的吗
You wanted me to look into it.
我没让你解释问题所在
I didn't ask you to explain the problem to me.
而是要你解决问题
I asked you to fix it for me.
路易真的杀人了吗
Did Louis really kill a guy?
这是你们助理之间传出的闲话吗
Is that what the associate rumor mill's been churning out?
实际上  我觉得是他挑的头
Actually, I think he started it.
他还声称自己1米88
He also claims that he's 6'2"
满头秀发
with a full head of hair.
满头秀发的路易  真有他的
Louis with hair. That's good.
你是怎么过唐娜那一关的
How'd you get past Donna?
你是趁她上厕所的时候进来的吧
You waited till she peed, didn't you?
那女人的憋尿功力了得
I mean, the woman retains water like a camel.
我发现
I see that the, uh,
你没有史上最伟大乐队的唱片
greatest band of all time is conspicuously absent.
你指的是哪个乐队  路易
And who would that be, Louis?
一个叫皇后的英国小乐队
I don't know. A little British band called Queen?
我早该料到你会这么说
Should have seen that coming.
真正的音乐家
You know, real musicians,
是不画眼线的
they don't wear eyeliner.
是吗  你怎么不去跟
Really? Why don't you tell that
摇滚歌手"王子"说说呢
to the artist formerly known as Prince,
他的本名就叫普林斯[王子]
Who's... once again named Prince?
你想干嘛  路易
What do you want, Louis?
既然我们一起工作
I think now that we're working together,
就得制定一些基本原则
we should set some ground rules.
原则一  永远别碰我的唱片
First rule, never touch my records.
以及这个办公室里的任何东西
or anything else in this office.
好吧
Fine.
包括这里的家具
That includes the furniture.
我想和你和睦相处
I'm trying to build a rapport with you.
好吗
Okay?
我们的关系还需要慢慢磨合
I mean, I think our relationship needs a little work.
等我们五周年结婚纪念的时候
Let's hold off the couples counseling
再考虑婚姻咨询吧
Until our fifth anniversary.
你觉得怎么样
Don't you think?
听着  马兹洛的律师加速了案件审理的进度
Look, Mazlo's lawyer moved to push up the trial.
他们知道我们需要时间寻找其他证人
They know we need time to cultivate another witness.
那我们就忽悠他们
I say we bluff.
我可以说  珀金斯的律师一走出房门
I mean, Perkins implicated Mazlo
就向马兹洛做出了暗示
the minute his lawyer walked out of the room.
那是瞎说  路易
That's hearsay, Louis.
如果这算临终忏悔的话就不一样了
Not if it's a deathbed confession.
我们还可以说  盖勒打报警电话的时候
Maybe while Geller was making the 911 call,
我和珀金斯说了几句话
I had a little conversation with Perkins.
对于珀金斯没说过的话和没做过的事
So you want to lie about what Perkins said
你打算瞎编吗
and how he said it?
那你有什么高见  哈维
What's your brilliant solution, Harvey?
根据之前说好的
I'm having the money
我准备查出珀金斯那笔钱的下落
in Perkins' account traced as we speak,
我也想到其他证人的人选了
and I have another witness in mind.
如果我能和安东尼・马兹洛当面对质
I get Anthony Mazlo across that table,
我一定能降服他
You know I'll break him.
就像你降服珀金斯那样吗
The way you broke Perkins?
对  如果有必要的话
Yeah. If need be.
你没明白我的意思
You're not hearing me.
我们现在最好不要安排任何会面
We need to hold off on any meeting.
-我只是想知道...  -就这么决定了  路易
- I just wanna know why-- - That's final, Louis.
提问  一个叫罗拉・詹森的人为什么
Question. Why would someone named Lola Jensen
想让别人误以为她是米德里德・维纽斯基
ever want to be known as Mildred Wisnewski?
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫迈克・罗斯  是名律师
My name's Mike Ross. I'm a lawyer.
让我猜猜  皮尔逊・哈德曼律所的吗
Let me guess. Pearson Hardman?
你知道吗  911事件后
You know, forging a government document
伪造政府批文的可能性微乎其微
like this after 911 is next to impossible.
天呐  二甲胺八成又出了点小问题
God, there must have been a glitch at the DMA.
你来这干什么
Why'd you come here?
你父亲来找过我们  他很担心你
Your father came to us 'cause he's worried about you.
他才不担心我  不然他就亲自过来了
He's not worried. He'd be here himself.
而不是派个无名小律师过来
He wouldn't have sent an empty suit.
你对我一无所知
You don't know anything about me.
而我却知道  你利用这张身份证
I, on the other hand, know that you used this I.D.
从清泉钻井公司窃取资金
to funnel payments from Clarity Drilling
注入你自己建立的冒名公司
to some fake company that you set up.
洛克斯利有限责任公司
Locksley LLC?
你在从父亲的公司窃取资金
You're stealing money from your father's company.
到目前为止  有200万了吧
Couple million so far.
我不需要知道原因
I don't need to know why,
但我要你立刻完璧归赵
but I do need you to return it. Now.
其实  你有必要知道原因
Actually, you do need to know why.
这是从突沙市南部
This is ground water
清泉公司那个天杀的工程中提取的地下水
from Clarity's fracking operation south of Tulsa.
亚乙基二醇二丁基  甲烷和苯的含量
It's got elevated levels of dibutoxyethanol,
严重超标
methane, and benzene.
这是钻井前水样的化学物质含量
This compares samples taken pre-drilling
和上周提取的对比图
to levels taken last week.
你怎么弄到的  那可是公司机密数据
How did you get that? That's classified company data.
你就当我是电脑高手吧
Let's just say I'm good with computers.
慢着  洛克斯利责任有限公司
Wait a minute. Locksley llc.
名称取自《盗侠罗宾汉》和《罗宾汉》吧
As in Robin of Locksley, as in Robin Hood.
这些毒素会导致肾衰竭
These toxins are known to cause kidney failure,
肝癌和不孕不育
liver cancer, and infertility.
环保署就此只做出了轻度处罚
The EPA fines were a slap on the wrist,
但是你们律所与受害者所商定的赔偿数目
but the settlement that your firm negotiated with the victims--
无论你的动机有多单纯
It doesn't matter how pure your motives are.
你都犯下了重罪
You're committing a very serious crime.
你就使劲地威胁我吧
Threaten all you want. Okay?
在我父亲的公司上市之前
There's no way that my father's gonna let this go public
他不会将此公之于众
right before his IPO.
我是不会把钱还回去的
I'm not giving the money back.
我会分发给受害者
I'm giving it away.
关于健在的亲属  我没有找到任何线索
In terms of living relatives, I didn't find anything,
但当我调查过世亲属遗留下的房产时
but when I looked into the estates of relatives who passed away,
发现E控股公司最初是以阿姨的名义登记的
E Holding was originally in the name of the aunt.
你对于珀金斯的假设是正确的
Your theory on Perkins is right.
哈维  你在干什么
Harvey, what are you doing?
瑞秋应该为我做事的
Rachel's services are under my purview.
抱歉  我不会让他得逞的
Sorry. I'm gonna change that.
安东尼・马兹洛和他的律师在会议室
Anthony Mazlo and his attorney are in the conference room.
谁让他们来的
At whose invitation?
你认为是我打电话让他们来的吗
What, you think I called 'em?
不是我
I--I didn't.
那就是马兹洛觉得他占了上风
Then Mazlo feels he has an advantage.
现在想乘胜追击
And he's pressing it.
各位
Fellas.
谢谢你们能这么快赶来接待我们
Thanks for meeting us on such short notice.
我还以为你在飞机上呢  马兹洛先生
I figured you'd be on a flight right now, Mr. Mazlo.
飞到没有引渡协议的地方
Somewhere with no extradition agreement.
我们直接说重点吧
Let's get to the point.
珀金斯不在了  你们就无法立案
Without Perkins, you don't have a case.
这是我们内部调查的总结报告
This report summarizes an internal investigation we conducted.
伊内兹递给你们的
What Inez has just handed you
就是珀金斯进行虚假投资
is hard evidence of fraudulent investments
和谎报损失的铁证
and fake losses perpetrated by Perkins.
你们有妄想症吧
Guys have a real penchant for fiction, don't you?
没有  是他骗了我们大家
No, he duped all of us.
作为执行总裁  他不但背叛了我
As CEO, he betrayed me
还背叛了所有投资人
just as much as the investors.
我们发现了一个存有两千万的离岸账户
We found an offshore account worth 20 million.
等等
Hold on a second.
露西尔・杰克森让你们管理
Lucille Jackson trusts you to manage
一亿五千万的捐赠基金
a $150 million endowment.
珀金斯拿了两千万  那其余的钱呢
Perkins takes 20. Where the hell's the rest of it?
鉴于目前的发现
In light of these findings,
我们想要进行和解
we'd like to offer a settlement.
一千五百万
15 million.
只给九牛一毛  真是耻辱
Ten cents on the dollar? That's a slap in the face.
我们提醒客户们投资有风险
Well, we advise all our clients that investments carry risk.
想要零风险回报  就去买国库券
You want a risk-free return, buy treasury bills,
或者把钱藏在床垫下面
or, I don't know, hide your money under the mattress.
在你天马流星编故事的时候
While you were writing the great American novel,
我却一直在调查事实
I've been checking facts.
珀金斯在海外账户上的两千万是合法所得
The 20 million that Perkins had overseas was legitimate.
他是无辜的
He was innocent.
你们公司被挪用的钱还未追回
The money your firm embezzled is still out there,
而这份所谓的调查报告
and this so-called investigation
纯属浪费纸张
isn't worth the paper it's printed on.
露西尔・杰克森不会同意的  律师
Well, Lucille Jackson may beg to differ, counselor.
申请过渡贷款说明她走投无路了
A bridge loan means she's desperate.
我们的条件没有商量余地
Our offer is non-negotiable.
这个条件我今天不会接受  以后也不会
I won't accept this offer today or a year from now.
既然你们不请自来
Now since you've all invited yourselves over,
也请自觉离开吧
feel free to see yourselves out.
刚才我想对珀金斯的事撒谎  你还教训我
So first you attack me for wanting to lie about Perkins,
结果一扭头就撒了谎  真是自打嘴巴
and then you turn around, do the same exact thing?
我没说谎
I wasn't lying.
你说什么
What are you saying to me?
哈维  你到底在说什么
Harvey, what the hell are you saying to me?
珀金斯没有参与此事吗
That Perkins had no involvement whatsoever?
我就是此意  路易
That's exactly what I'm saying, Louis.
他是无辜的
He was innocent.
马兹洛对我们虚报低价也不奇怪
It's no surprise that Mazlo low-balled us.
我只是按规定传述条件
I'm just passing along this offer as a formality.
一千五百万不是什么小数目
$15 million is not insignificant.
但现在不是和解的时候
But now's not the time to settle.
我们必须坚持立场
We have to strengthen our hand.
好吧  我有个问题
All right, here's my problem.
最佳情况是
Best-case scenario.
我们上庭  陪审团判决和解
We go to trial, the jury awards us a settlement,
显然  马兹洛更希望如此
obviously Mazlo appeals that.
那样的话  我三年都别想拿到钱
It's three years before I see any money,
而到时我的基金早就没了
and my foundation's long gone by that point.
不  我不会让马兹洛
No, I'm not gonna let Mazlo
分走你捐赠基金的最大份额
pocket the lion's share of your endowment.
我可不想得不偿失
I'm not interested in a Pyrrhic victory.
我们也是
Neither are we.
为了表明诚意  我们打算先动用平日收费
And to prove it, we're gonna forego our usual fee,
并返还你已付的费用
and return to you the money you've already paid.
我从小睡在我妈的车里
I grew up sleeping in my mama's car.
我们住过的小客栈  数都数不过来
And in and out of more halfway houses than I can count,
我从中悟出的道理就是每一分钱都很宝贵
and one thing I realized is that every penny matters.
所以我要谢谢你们
So thank you.
你要怎么做
What you gonna do?
珀金斯也许是无辜的
Perkins may have been innocent,
但他还是马兹洛的直属部下
but he was still Mazlo's direct report.
我要弄清他知道些什么
I'm gonna find out what he knew.
你们的工作就是核查马兹洛
Your job is to verify every detail
内部调查的每一个细节
of Mazlo's internal investigation.
不是要查犯罪细节  而是他们所掩盖的事实
It is not about the crime now. It's about the cover-up.
这上面说珀金斯独来独往
This says Perkins acted alone.
他是个完美的替罪羊
Well, he's the perfect scapegoat.
他不能为自己辩护了
He can't defend himself.
你想去厕所吗
You want to go to the bathroom?
去了就别回来了
You don't bother coming back.
另外还不准打私人电话  发私人电邮和短信
By the way, that goes for personal phone calls, emails, and texts.
一旦发现有所懈怠
I detect a whiff of slacking,
你们就完了  明白了吗
you are done. Get it?
我在办公室  有线索告诉我
You find anything, I'll be in my office.
路易  我还在跟哈维的案件
Louis. Uh, I'm still working on Harvey's case.
杰罗姆・詹森死了都跟我没关系
Jerome Jensen can go screw himself for all I care.
哈维明确跟我说
Well, Harvey explicitly told me--
谁跟你说的我都不管  迈克
I don't care if a burning bush told you, Mike.
你现在唯一需要遵从的
The only commandments you need to focus on right now
是我的命令
come from me.
路易很不对劲
There's something wrong with Louis.
不是我的问题  我只听哈维的
It's not my problem. I answer to Harvey.
回家看孩子去吧  你被开除了
Sitting home alone with your kids, with no job.
哈维
Harvey.
你解决完杰罗姆的问题了吗
You solve Jerome's problem yet?
快了  我现在需要你的工卡
Uh, about to. But I need your corporate card first.
为什么
What for?
你不是不想听我解释吗
Well, I thought you didn't want me to explain it to you.
没错  我不想听
You're right. I don't.
行了
Okay.
不知道我要用这个做什么
It's killing you not knowing
你很难受吧
what I'm gonna use this for, isn't it?
不会
Nope.
让我告诉你吧
Please let me tell you.
如果你还卡的时候  上面有脱衣舞女的味道
If you bring that back to me and it smells like stripper,
你就被开除了
you're fired.
我不去那种地方
I don't--I don't go to places like that.
你一定要派人来吗
You had to send someone?
就不能直接打给我
Couldn't just call me?
如果你想要不被发现
If you wanted this to be private,
你就该直接打劫我
should have just robbed me.
你挪用了公款  我就不得不牵扯进其他人
You robbed the company, I had to involve other people.
不如我们坐下谈吧
Okay. Why don't we take a seat?
你找我过来干什么
Why are you here?
我想要告诉你一些事情
I want to tell you my side of things.
行
Okay.
对于污染水源的事情我并不引以为豪
I'm not proud of the fact that we contaminated people's water.
但我们已经道过歉了
But we apologized.
也落实了安全措施
We implemented safeguards.
同时还兑现了慷慨至极的赔偿
We negotiated a payout that was more than generous.
如果你真这么想  那你就是在自欺欺人
If that's what you think, then you are lying to yourself.
我觉得我们该心平气和一点
I think that we could keep this civil--
不  她说的对  确实
No, she's right. It's true.
我在自欺欺人
I am lying to myself.
我以为这只是阶段性的
I thought this was a phase,
是荷尔蒙作怪  一切都会过去
that it was hormones, that it would pass,
但事实是
but the truth is...
我养了一个贼
I raised a thief.
给我们点时间  谢谢
Okay, I think we're gonna need a minute. Thank you.
贼是吗
A thief.
我的研究致力于让地球更适于居住
My research is making the planet more habitable, okay?
而你却在搞破坏并从中牟利
You are making money destroying it.
你不尊重我  不要紧
You have no respect for me, that's fine.
但起码请尊重一下那些工人
But at least respect the workers.
你偷的也是他们的血汗钱
You're stealing from them too.
你觉得我身负此等大罪是吗
You think I'm such a criminal?
那就抓我啊
Arrest me.
我安排这次见面是为了让你们消除误会
So I organized this so that you two could clear the air,
不过我们似乎越走越偏了
and it seems we've gotten off the wrong foot...
你知道吗  老爸  这次还是老样子
You know what? It's the same story as always, dad.
你永远都在回避责任
You duck your responsibilities.
罗拉
Lo--Lola.
我用自己的钱还给公司如何
What if I paid the company back with my own money?
我不认为这是个好主意
I don't think that would be a very good idea.
这会让你成为同谋
It would make you a conspirator.
我不能把女儿交给警察
I'm not turning my daughter into the police.
这无关公司商誉
This is not about the company image.
好消息是她还没开始散钱
Well, the good news is, she hasn't distributed the money--
不关钱的事
The money is irrelevant.
我请皮尔逊・哈德曼律所帮忙解决此事
I came to Pearson Hardman to take care of this.
可我女儿反而和我渐行渐远
Instead, my daughter and I are further apart than ever.
我简直无法想象你所要面对的一切
I can't imagine how hard it is right now.
现在关于埃利奥特的流言四起
People are saying the most horrible things about Elliot.
他们一定以为我聋了
They must think I've gone deaf.
安东尼・马兹洛还在利用你丈夫
Anthony Mazlo has been dragging your husband's name
让他做替罪羊  珀金斯夫人
through the mud to make him a scapegoat, Mrs. Perkins.
我是来帮忙的
I'm here to help.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你是另一边的人
You work for the other side.
我同样效力于某资金被全部窃取的慈善机构
I work for a charitable organization that had all its money stolen.
我的对立方是安东尼・马兹洛
I'm on the other side of Anthony Mazlo,
不是你丈夫
not your husband,
我不希望看到他的名声被抹黑
and I don't want to see his memory painted with the same brush.
需要我做什么
What would I have to do?
现在说这个不合时宜
This isn't the time or the place.
不  没关系  我该怎么做
No, it's okay. What would I have to do?
我想知道埃利奥特跟你说过的
I'd like to know everything
任何关于马兹洛的事情
Elliot has ever told you about Mazlo.
每个细节都很重要
Any details would help.
珀金斯夫人  我是路易・利特
Ms Perkins, uh, I'm Louis Litt.
我想告诉您
And I just want to let you know
我一定会竭尽所能  为您的丈夫正名
that I'm going to do whatever it takes to clear your husband's name.
正名
His name?
要不是因为你  我丈夫现在还健在
My husband would be alive today if it weren't for you.
话可不能这么说
Well, we don't know that.
我知道那天发生了什么
I know what happened in that room.
当时我们并不了解所有的真相
Well, at the time, we didn't have all the facts,
但现在我们清楚了
but now we do.
我真不敢相信你居然有脸到这里来
I can't believe that you have the audacity to come here.
我这辈子也不想再见到你
I don't ever want to see your face again.
你也别琢磨着让我帮忙了
And you can forget about me helping you.
你这是搞什么鬼啊
What the hell are you doing?
我跟你一样  在向遗孀取证
I was deposing the widow, just like you.
我来到这里表示慰问  建立友好关系
I came here to pay my respects and initiate a relationship,
而不是激怒一位悲痛欲绝的妇女
not aggravate a grieving woman.
我也是  我还买了花
Yeah, I brought flowers.
你让我们失去了一位潜在证人
You just cost us a potential witness.
真的吗
Oh, really?
也许你该事先告诉我你的计划
Well, maybe--maybe if you shared your game plan with me--
就像你这样冷不丁地来一出一样吗
Oh, the same way that you shared your game plan with me?
你以为她见到你的反应该是如何
How do you expect her to react to seeing you?
你最好卯足劲  给我们找个新的证人
You need to get your shit together and find us a new witness.
罗拉
Lola.
我来为之前的事道歉
Wanted to apologize for earlier today.
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
当然
Uh, yeah. Of course.
很有心嘛  选园林作为见面地点
Nice gesture. Botanical gardens.
是啊  他说你们俩对那里有特殊的感情
Yeah, he said it was a pretty special place for you guys.
的确如此  接着他就成了总裁
It was. And then he became CEO.
我可不是来这追忆往事的
But I'm not here to reminisce.
我不得不赞叹一下
I must say I was, uh, really impressed
你竟然猜出了我的想法
you figured out what I was doing.
尤其是你还算不上一位正牌律师
Especially since you're not even a real lawyer.
你这话什么意思
What--what are you talking about?
我查看了哈佛法学院男毕业生名录
I accessed Harvard law school's alumni directory.
过去十年毕业生的所有记录
Every class that graduated for the last ten years.
压根没有叫迈克・罗斯的
No record of Mike Ross. At all.
是  院长办公室本该修正的
Yeah, the dean's office was supposed to fix that.
他们把我的名字登记错了
They--they put my name wrong in the system.
我将你的社保号与数据库做了对比
I checked your social security number against the database.
你怎么会知道我的社保号
How'd you get my social security number?
小事一桩  你听好
Easily. Here's the deal.
别插手我的事  不然我就揭发你
Leave me alone, or I expose you.
你好像完全不担心这事
You don't really seem that worried about this.
她恐吓你  这是个策略
Threats like hers are a tactic.
这招很有效  因为它会把你的注意力
They're effective because they distract you
从正事上分散开
from what you're supposed to be doing.
你是疯了吗
Are you crazy?
我们该做的是赶紧躲远点吧
What we should be doing is backing the hell off.
那之后会怎么样呢
And how would that go, huh?
杰罗姆  你找我们帮忙
"Jerome, you came to us with the problem,"
我们发现你的女儿
"we discovered that your daughter"
从贵公司盗走了两百万
"stole $2 million from your company,"
而我们的结论是你太他妈倒霉了
"and our conclusion is you're shit out of luck"?
我一点也不在乎结果怎样
I don't really care how it would go.
我只在乎的自己的人生
All I care about is my life,
以及守住我们的秘密
and--and keeping our secret.
我跟你说了  这只不过是个策略
I told you, it's a distraction.
她不会真干的
She won't pull that trigger.
你以为她为何迟迟不把那笔资金散出去
Why do you think she hasn't distributed that money yet?
你以为杰罗姆为何不想我们联络警方
Why do you think Jerome doesn't want us to go to the police?
我不知道
I don't know.
因为他们双方都希望能冰释前嫌
It's because they both want to bury the hatchet,
而一旦动了真格  就和解不了了
And if any of that stuff happens, they can't.
我们该怎么办
Then what?
想办法让他们握手言和咯
Figure out a way to make them reconcile.
就这么简单
It's easy.
是够简单的
Yeah. It's easy.
是伊内兹吗  我是路易・利特
Inez, right? Louis litt.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
这就是你为马兹洛做的工作吗
So is this what you do for Mazlo?
你负责洗他的脏衣服
You clean up his dirty laundry?
离我远点
Leave me alone.
你知道自己前途无量吗
You know, you have your whole career ahead of you.
到时候马兹洛倒了台  你作为帮凶
Mazlo goes down and you're part of this cover-up,
没人会肯雇你
no one's gonna hire you.
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
我能告诉你些事吗  伊内兹
Listen, can I just tell you something, Inez?
以我的经验来看  人会被两种手段驱使
In my experience, people respond to two things, okay?
那就是利诱和威逼
And that's the carrot and the stick.
现在我更倾向于来硬的
Now, I prefer the stick,
因此如果你不帮我
and if you do not help me,
我会用我丰富的专业经验来让你就范
I will devote my considerable expertise to sticking it to you.
就像逼迫珀金斯那样吗
The same way you stuck it to Perkins.
伊内兹  等等
Inez, stop.
咱们还是谈谈条件吧
Let's go with the carrot.
伊内兹  我是哈维・斯佩克特
Inez, Harvey Specter.
很感激你能前来
I appreciate you coming forward.
我早就该来了
I should have done it sooner.
为什么改变了呢
What changed?
我再也受不了在那公司做事了
I can't be a part of a company like that anymore.
你准备好在公开法庭上举证
Are you ready to testify against Anthony Mazlo
安东尼・马兹洛了吗
in open court?
是的
I am.
你应该有指证他违法渎职的文件资料吧
I assume you've documented his malfeasance.
不然的话就是口说无凭
Because otherwise it's he said, she said.
全部的书面记录
The entire paper trail.
从最开始到上个星期的
From the beginning all the way to last week.
哈维让我解决罗拉的问题
Harvey asked me to fix this problem with Lola,
但我做不到
but I can't.
因为令爱并非问题所在  詹森先生
Because your daughter's not the problem, Mr. Jensen.
你才是
You are.
你是想被炒鱿鱼吗
Are you trying to get fired?
不  我不是
No. I'm not.
我是你的代理人
I'm your attorney.
为你提建议是我的职责
It's my job to give you advice.
但你是她的父亲
But you're her father.
对孩子的悉心培养是你的职责
It's your job to raise her.
你大可以更换代理律所
Now, you can go to another firm,
但是世上没有哪位律师
but there's not a lawyer in the city
能替你完成这份职责
that can do that job for you.
请不要在为人父母这个问题上教育我
Please don't lecture me on parenting.
詹森先生  我曾与我父亲关系恶劣
Mr. Jensen, I had a difficult relationship with my father,
所以请相信我  罗拉是想原谅你的
so trust me when I tell you that Lola wants to forgive you,
但她需要你先退一步
but she needs you to take the first step.
我们也试过了
Well, we tried it your way.
一起共进午饭  你也目睹结果了
We went to lunch, and you saw how well that worked out.
我女儿不是小孩子了
My daughter's not a child.
她是个成年人
She's an adult.
也以成年人的身份做了这些决定
She made these choices as an adult.
如果你能找到办法
If you just found a way...
你是我的律师  我与你只谈法律
You're my lawyer. This is a legal problem.
我女儿的行为是她自己的选择
My daughter brought this on herself.
现在尽管我极不情愿她坐牢
Now, I desperately do not want her to go to prison.
但如果她不把钱还回来  她就蹲定了
But if she doesn't return the money, she will.
马兹洛在哪
Where's Mazlo?
他不敢亲自面对我们吗
He was afraid to face us himself?
你们想怎么样
What do you want?
我们知道你们的整个计划
We know about your entire scheme.
什么计划
What scheme?
马兹洛去迪拜洗黑钱的计划
Oh, the scheme where Mazlo's laundering money through Dubai.
你怎么知道迪拜的事
How do you know about Dubai?
我们有了新的信息源
We cultivated another source.
你们希望怎样和解
What kind of settlement are you looking for?
至少要有惩罚性损害赔偿金吧
One that includes punitive damages.
让伊内兹进来
Send Inez in here, please.
我想你应该找不到她吧
I don't think you'll find her at her desk.
怎么会
Why not?
她同意为我们作证了
'Cause she agreed to testify for us.
我深表怀疑
I doubt that.
你同事联络她时
When your colleague approached her,
她直接汇报给了我们
she came straight to us.
他甚至想要贿赂我
He even tried to bribe me.
他说如果我出卖马兹洛先生
He said if I ratted out Mr. Mazlo,
就能让我做杰西卡・皮尔逊的助手
he'd get me a job as an assistant to Jessica Pearson.
她告诉你的每件事都是假的
Everything she told you is a complete fabrication.
根本就没有什么迪拜
There is no Dubai.
让我来提醒一下你们
I seem to recall you mentioning something
我们在上次会面中提到的对伪证的处罚
about penalties for perjury at our last meeting.
对于贿赂证人的处罚将更加严重
Well, the penalty for bribing a witness is just as severe.
我们乐意忽略此次轻率行为
And we're willing to overlook that indiscretion
只要你们能说服你们的客户接受和解条款
if you convince your client to take our settlement offer.
当然了  是重新修订的和解条款
Well, our revised settlement offer.
-重新修订的  -没错
- Revised? - Yes.
也就是之前所说的一半金额
Exactly half of what it was before.
你到底怎么想的啊
What the hell were you thinking?
我们需要新的证人
We needed a new witness.
你就没想到要查查她的底吗
You didn't think to look into her story?
不知道  你查了吗
I don't know. Did you look into it?
是你带她来的
You were the one who brought her in.
我以为你查了呢
I assumed you had.
就算一个二把刀的律师也知道要查吧
Like any halfway decent lawyer would.
我们形势严峻
We were under the gun.
况且有人颐指气使地给我下死命令
And I was under strict instructions from my golf pro
让我再去找个证人来
to get another witness.
我是让你找个证人
No, I told you to get another witness,
不是买个来
not bribe one.
够了
That's enough.
尽管路易被要挟
As for the threat against Louis,
至少资金还没有转移
no money changed hands.
我担心的不是路易
I'm not concerned with Louis.
他把你也牵扯进来了  懂吗
He brought your name into it, okay?
他提的条件是给你做助理
The offer was to be your assistant.
这样就等于把你拉下水了
Now you're exposed because of what he did.
这是真的吗
Is that true?
她是大投资公司头头的行政助理
She's an executive assistant to the head of a major investment firm.
怎么可能让她屈尊给初级合伙人打工
She's not gonna work for a junior partner.
所以你就试图贿赂她
So you tried to bribe her.
我那不是贿赂  杰西卡
No, it wasn't a bribe, Jessica.
只是想激她一下
It was an incentive.
我觉得要想让她开口
I thought she'd be more likely to talk
就必须免除她被解雇的顾忌
if she wasn't worried about getting fired.
你去马兹洛那里接受他们的条件吧
I want you to go to Mazlo and take their offer.
-我还不想那么做  -我也是
- I'm not ready to do that. - I'm not either.
我退回露西尔的佣金
I waived Lucille's fee
是因为某个资深合伙人
because a certain senior partner
说这事不会闹上法庭
said we'd never go to trial.
这话是在你把路易塞给我之前说的
I said that before you stuck me with Louis.
那不是重点
Not the point.
她输不起  我们也一样
She can't afford it, and neither can we.
给我点时间
Give me time.
让我来办  路易别插手
Give it to me without Louis,
我们走着瞧  看看输不起的是谁
and we'll see who can afford it and who can't.
到今晚截止
You have until the end of the day.
你若一无所获
You come up empty,
我就亲自去找露西尔谈
I'm taking the offer to Lucille myself.
杰西卡  我去找珀金斯...
Jessica. I went to Perkins--
一个字也别说了
Not another word.
你再敢那么干
You try something like that again,
就收拾包袱走人吧
and it will be your last day at this firm.
你说杰罗姆不会动真格
You said Jerome wouldn't pull the trigger.
你错了  他已经蓄势待发了
You were wrong. He's ready.
我现在没工夫管那个
I don't have time for that right now.
哈维  等警察找上罗拉
Harvey, when the police show up at Lola's doorstep,
我们就完了
we're done.
她把钱送出去了吗
Has she distributed the money yet?
不  还没呢  不过她
No, she hasn't, but she's--
还没  也不会
She hasn't, and she won't,
因为她想要的是她老爸的注意力
because what she wants is her daddy's attention.
你坐下  我们处理这件事
Now sit down with me, and let's deal with this.
好  好吧
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
说说你要我做什么吧
Why don't you tell me what you need?
露西尔的捐款不翼而飞的当天
Mazlo was in Liechtenstein the day that
马兹洛人在列支敦士登
Lucille's endowment evaporated.
或许他去滑雪了
Maybe he was skiing.
才没人去列支敦士登度假呢
Nobody goes to Liechtenstein for pleasure.
我们为什么不发传票索取银行记录
Why don't we subpoena the bank records?
那里能有多少银行
How many banks can there be?
那地方比瑞士还恐怖[银行多]
Place is like Switzerland on steroids.
我们不可能拿到那些记录
We'll never see those records.
那你他妈到底要我做什么
So what the hell do you want from me, then?
你刚刚说什么
What did you just say to me?
我曾提议黑进哈佛的资料库来办妥我的事
I once suggested that we hack Harvard's records to cover my ass,
可你不屑一顾
and you laughed at me.
现在证明你错了
And now it turns out that you were wrong,
而我就要为此饭碗不保
and it's about to cost me my career.
你去哪
Where are you going?
你让我解决我的案子
You told me to fix my case.
那你也自己解决吧
Why don't you fix yours?
希望你是来告诉我哈维不再多管闲事了
Hope you came here to tell me Harvey's backing off.
我也希望  可惜非也
I wish I could, but he's not.
真是可惜了你的似锦前程
That's too bad. Had such a promising career.
老天  罗拉
Oh, my god, Lola,
你装得像个圣人君子
you act like you care about a higher cause,
可这么多公司  你偏选了你爸爸的
but of all the companies that exist, you chose your dad's.
而这家公司还试着弥补他们的过失
Company that's trying to make amends for what it did.
我才懒得听你这种朝衣冠禽兽努力的人
Really don't need to hear another speech
给我上大课
from a wanna-be suit.
天啊  你觉得我是你的敌人  是吗
God, you think I'm your enemy, huh?
我不是
Well, I'm not.
我不是来和你谈我  或你父亲的
I didn't even come here to talk to you about me or your father.
纽约  爱荷华  堪萨斯
New york. Iowa. Kansas.
四十个州都有即将成为泡影的住宅计划
40 states that all have housing projects that will vanish
而只有你能帮我们找出所需信息
if we don't find out information that only you can help us get.
你可以偷你爸公司的钱
So you can steal money from your father's company
也可以去告发我
or you can blow the whistle on me if you want to,
但如果你是真的关心你所声称的那些人
but if you really care about people the way that you claim to,
这才是你该先做的
you're gonna do this first.
有收获吗
Are we close?
我在通过天朝的服务器进入银行
I'm accessing the banks through a server in China.
莫非你想我就用你这边的
Unless you'd rather me use yours.
-慢慢来  -进去了
- Take your time. - Done.
列支敦士登有十六家银行
All right, there's 16 banks in Liechtenstein.
这里列有每家银行的每个账户
This is every account in every single one of them.
没有一个账户在安东尼・马兹洛名下
None of the accounts is listed under Anthony Mazlo.
别管名字了
Forget about the name.
找到安厦建筑的资金被盗那天
Find an account with $150 million
户头上多了一亿五千万的账户
embezzled from Stable Shelters on that day.
哈维  时间到了
Harvey, it's time.
你要是没查到什么
Unless you have something,
我就打电话找露西尔来和解了
I'm calling Lucille to settle.
杰西卡  你知道列支敦士登
Jessica, you know how Liechtenstein
完全不理会传票
doesn't respond to subpoenas,
所以我就主动上门了
so I've responded for them.
相信我
Just trust me.
要找到露西尔的钱  我们已万事俱备
We've got everything we need to find Lucille's money.
没在这里
It's not here.
看来你一时半会儿搞不定
Sounds like you need more than just another minute.
你果真是欠东风
You need another person.
你需要一个精通金融犯罪的人
Someone whose expertise is financial crime.
不  不
No. No.
哈维  去找路易
Harvey, bring in Louis.
不然我就给露西尔打电话
Or I'm calling Lucille.
唐娜  我要跟路易谈谈
Donna, I need to talk to Louis.
他不在办公室
He's not in his office.
怎么  诺玛不告诉你他在哪吗
huh. Norma wouldn't tell you where he is?
她没有...
Well, she didn't, um...
你就没问吧
You didn't ask her, did you?
她让我毛骨悚然的
She gives me the creeps.
你可真是个软蛋
Ugh. You're such a wuss.
你刚刚说什么
What did you just say to me?
少装没听到
I think we both know what I just said.
诺玛  他在哪
Norma, where is he?
什么  你开玩笑呢吧
What? You're kidding.
怎么了
What?
我需要一个人静静时就来这里
I come here when I need to be alone.
点44马格南
.44 magnum?
你当真
Really?
今天很有感觉吗  小阿飞
Feeling lucky today, punk?
我知道
You know, I understand
我把案子搞砸了
that me pissing the bed on this case
你一定心里暗爽
must be really, really fun for you.
不  路易  不是这样的
No. Louis, it's not.
我们唯一的共同点
The one thing you and I have in common
就是我们都需要赢
is we need to win.
这我知道
I noticed that.
我来这里是因为  尽管事态不好
I came here because, even after everything,
我们还是能赢
we can win.
不
No.
是我只能看着你赢
I can watch while you win.
路易  我不是来跟你闲扯的
Louis, I'm not here to give you shit.
听我说  我尊敬你
Listen, I respect you.
我贿赂证人
I bribed a witness.
你是想激她一下
You incentivized her.
我去找了珀金斯的遗孀
Went to see Perkins' widow.
是想道歉
To apologize.
我害死了个人
I killed a man.
你知道他本就大限将至
That you thought had it coming.
我想你没听到我的话
I don't think you heard what I said.
我尊敬你
I respect you.
你是需要我帮忙
You need my help.
我倒不会那么说
I wouldn't phrase it exactly like that.
如果你需要我帮忙
Well, if you need my help,
你最好斟字酌句说清楚了
you better phrase it exactly like that.
好吧  你想我开口是吗
Okay. You want me to say it?
那我就说
I'll say it.
现在迫在眉睫了  我需要你的帮助
I'm under the gun, and I need your help.
我有信息资源
I've got information,
而你有解决案子所需的金融专业头脑
and you've got the financial expertise to break this case.
咱们把抢放下  去收拾他们吧
Now let's put the gun down and go get 'em.
好的
Okay.
你先站前面去
First just stand over there.
别得寸进尺
Don't push it.
安厦建筑的账户究竟
So what was the exact amount of money
损失了多少金额
that was lost from Stable Shelters' account?
为什么问这个
Why?
1亿5千237万5千242美元18美分
$152,375,242.18.
我很擅长数字活儿
I'm good with numbers.
说说你查到些什么
All right. What do you have?
列支敦士登十六家银行
We've compiled a printout of every account
出事那天所有有过存款记录的账户
that had a deposit made on the day in question
资料都打印出来了
in all of Liechtenstein's 16 banks.
好的  我们要专攻  借用一下
Okay. Well, we are going to focus on, excuse me...
这五家银行
these five banks.
你凭什么确定
How can you be sure?
听好了
Watch this.
这四家银行曾屈服于法庭压力
These four banks have a history of capitulating to subpoenas.
马兹洛事先会搞清楚
So Mazlo would know.
这六家在美国有母公司
These six have U.S. corporate parents,
使他们受制于联邦政府监管
which would expose their accounts to federal scrutiny.
同样  马兹洛也知道
Once again, Mazlo would know.
然后这边的这家银行储备金不足
And then the one that he's got right there is low in reserves,
意味着偿付能力有限
therefore its solvency's in question,
而马兹洛绝不可能把挪用的款项
and there is no way in hell that Mazlo would take his stolen money
存进一家摇摇欲坠的银行
and put it into some shaky bank.
所以我们能够确定
So we can be sure.
那些盗用公款的人
Every person who embezzles money,
都有一套自己独特的行事风格
they do it in their own way.
但他们的共同之处
But the one thing that they all have in common
在于他们绝不会孤注一掷
is that they never put all their eggs in one basket.
因此我们面对的会是多个账户组合的情况
So we are going to be looking at a combination of accounts.
横跨不同银行
Across banks.
也许是不同的银行
Well, I mean, maybe across banks.
也有可能是同一家
Maybe the same bank.
但肯定会有多个账户
But we're definitely looking at more than one account.
那我们如何识别出哪些账户是他的
How do we figure out which accounts are his?
凭总和  因为所有账户的资金
Because they're all gonna add up
加和后的总量必然
to the same exact amount of money
和安厦建筑损失的金额一致
that was lost from Stable Shelters' account.
你怎么知道
Well, how do you know?
有出必有入
When the account was drained, it had to go somewhere.
露西尔所失必然等于马兹洛所得
What goes out from Lucille's had to go into Mazlo's.
很简单的数学法则
Simple law of mathematics.
那么我们只需要找到账户组合
So we just have to figure out a combination of accounts
总量等于...
that adds up to...
1亿5千237万5千242美元18美分
$152,375,242.18.
我也擅长数字活儿
I'm good with numbers too.
感谢你们能立刻前来
Thanks for meeting us on such short notice.
我猜你们是准备接受我们的出价了
Well, I assume you're ready to take our offer.
于是飞奔过来了
I rushed right down.
在那之前  我们还有
Well, we just have a few questions
几个问题需要确认
before we get to any of that.
我们不接受任何询问
We didn't agree to answer any questions.
不  不  罗伯特  不要紧
No, no, robert, it's okay.
我乐意奉陪
I'm happy to play.
马兹洛先生  你去过列支敦士登吗
Have you ever been to Liechtenstein, Mr. Mazlo?
我去过很多地方
You know, I've been to many places.
其中包括列支敦士登
Among them, Liechtenstein.
真的吗  那么在众多去处中
Really? Well, of those many places,
你是否曾设立七个不同的银行账户
did you open seven different bank accounts,
存款总额与露西尔・杰克森的
the amounts of which add up to exactly the same amount of money
资助基金消失的金额完全相同呢
that disappeared from Lucille Jackson's endowment fund?
我表示怀疑  但能肯定的是
I doubt it. Uh, what I don't doubt
如果你查查那些账户的资金来源
is that if you trace the money that went into those accounts,
你会发现它们都来自于
you'll find that it came
我们公司在斯里兰卡的办事处
from our corporate offices in Sri Lanka.
完全合法
It's completely legitimate.
我非常乐意出示交易记录
I mean, I'm happy to show you the records, uh,
你们随时都可以审查
whenever you'd like.
多和谐  不是吗
That's great. Isn't that great?
在那之后  你能否再给我们看看
Well, after that, can you show us the records
当天你在那几家银行
of the seven safety deposit boxes
开设的七个保险箱的记录呢
that you opened at those same banks the same day?
我不需要回答
I don't have to answer that.
这不是取证
This isn't a deposition.
你说的很对  这更像是在表态
You're so right. It's more of a presentation.
我们也可以弄成取证
We could make it a deposition.
-或是庭审  -由你决定
- Or trial. - up to you.
我们手上有你进入那些银行的照片
We have pictures of you entering those banks.
我们也完全有能力传唤他们作证
And we have enough to crack their subpoenas.
只是早晚而已  托尼
Just a matter of time, Tony.
好吧  你想怎么样
All right. What do you want?
我想怎么...  这和我无关
What do I wa--? Well, it's not about me.
露西尔才是关键
It's about Lucille.
她想要你游街示众
She wants your head on a stick
要她和解有两个条件
But she'll settle
一是钱物归原主
for her money back.
二是你递交辞呈
And your resignation.
只要我们在这里达成一致
We agree right here,
就不会有刑事诉讼对吗
no criminal prosecution?
成交
Done.
如果露西尔今天没拿回她的资金
If Lucille doesn't get her money back today,
一切协议作废
nothing's done.
很好  非常好
Great. That's perfect.
你可以正常营业了
You are back in business.
资金已经汇过来了
The wire transfer just went through.
你挺过来了  姑娘
Girl, you came through.
我们就是做这个的
That is what we do.
哈维  哈维  进来
Harvey. Harvey, get in here.
露西尔想当面谢谢你
Lucille wants to thank you in person.
必须有时间接受感激嘛
Always got time for gratitude.
哈维  你当初没让我和解
Harvey, you didn't let me settle,
我很欣赏你的毅力
and I appreciate your tenacity.
事实是  这不是我一个人办成的
Truth is, I didn't do this on my own.
你认识路易・利特吗
Have you met Louis Litt?
你们干得真漂亮
You guys are doing such good work.
我只是想让你们知道
I just want you to know it.
我说过你是公司不可多得的人才吗
Have I told you how valuable you are to this company?
因为你不是  开个玩笑
'Cuz you're not. I'm just kidding.
詹尼斯  今天放你一天假
Janice, I want you to take the rest of the day off
因为你很棒  我是认真的
because you're so good. And I really mean it.
霍华德  九点半  龙舌兰
Howard, 9:30, Tequila shots.
你和我  准时到那
You and me. Sharp. Be there.
路易  小路易
Louis. Luiz.
怎么了
What's up?
你在那里做什么
What were you just doing in there?
什么  我只是在...
What? I was just...
让我猜猜  你在排挤我
Let me guess. You were cutting me out.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你和杰西卡还有露西尔开小会
The little impromptu meeting you just had with Jessica and Lucille
轻而易举地将我排挤在外
that you conveniently left me out of.
我没有在任何事情上排挤你啊
I didn't leave you out of anything.
我还以为我们是一个团队
I mean, I thought we were a team.
我以为我们的关系翻开了新的篇章
I thought this was the start of something,
但是我...
but I--
现在我总算看清了
Now I see the truth all too clearly.
路易  我只是路过
Louis, I was walking by,
她们叫我进去而已
and they called me in.
没错  正赶上时机将我所做的归功于你
Yeah, just in time to take the credit for what I did.
我可没那么做
I didn't do that.
一丁点这种想法都没有
Wouldn't even think of doing that.
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
你会这么想  这就是你的问题
You would, and that's your problem right there.
收到你那封关于马兹洛的邮件了
Got your email about Mazlo.
可以让洛克斯利有限责任公司完美散场了
Not a bad way for Locksley Llc to go out.
看来公司欠你一个人情
Looks like the firm owes you one.
欠我人情的是你吧
I think you owe me one.
哈佛学位证书  迈克・詹姆斯・罗斯  法学博士
-这是  -货真价实
- Is this... - The real thing?
没错
Yeah.
我通知院长办公室说你的丢失了
Told the dean's office you'd lost yours,
而他们乐意为优秀毕业生效劳
and they were happy to oblige for one of their top graduates.
真不知道我是该崇拜你还是畏惧你
I don't know if you're awesome or terrifying.
我还给你加了固
Also I added a layer of protection for you.
这不是哈佛法学院的校友库吗
Uh, the Harvard Law School alumni database?
都在那  你的名字  班级排名
It's all there. Your name, class rank,
社保号
Social security number.
你应该知道你让我成犯罪同伙了  对吗
You do realize you just made me party to a crime, right?
你可以随时电话问询
Can always call 'em up,
就说出故障了
report it as a glitch.
让我猜猜  无法追溯
Let me guess. Untraceable.
我不是说你不会被抓住
I'm not saying you won't get caught,
但不会因资料不符被抓
but it won't be because your story doesn't check.
谢谢你
Thank you.
真的
Seriously.
你是对的
You're right.
是该和我爸爸应该好好相处
Working things out with my dad.
你并非我想的那样徒有衣表
Not the empty suit I thought you were.
那是谁
Who was that?
客户的女儿
Uh, client's daughter.
真的吗  天色已晚
Really? It's kind of late.
这个时候她来办公室做什么
What's she doing at the office at this hour?
她只是专程来感谢我
You know, she was, uh, just thanking me.
-感谢你  -是的
- Thanking you. - Mm-hmm.
她谢得如何
How'd she do that?
很随意
Easily.
她给我买了两张去希腊的机票
She bought me two tickets to Greece.
不感兴趣
Not interested.
我们周二出发
We leave tuesday.